# Koladele Olaitan

Front-end Developer & Technical Writer/Blogger

in LinkedIn

+2347081540289

Portfolio

GitHub

Blog

### **About**

I'm a Front-end Developer with over 3 years of experience making the web better by deploying amazing web applications with a portfolio to show for it. I use my skills to build first-class, mobile-responsive, speed-optimized, and accessible websites. I love open-source!

#### **Technical Skills**

- Markup: Semantic HTML, JSX.
- UI & Styling: CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Material Design, Figma, Adobe XD.

•

No-code Tools: WordPress, Elementor, MailChimp.

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript.
- Libraries and Frameworks: React, Next.js, GSAP, Axios, Swiper.js, Leaflet.js, Chart.js.
- Bundlers & Linters: Webpack, Parcel, ESLint, Prettier.
- Hosting & OS: Netlify, Vercel, cPanel, Linux (preferred), MacOS, Windows.
- Additional: NPM, Technical documentation, REST APIs, Responsive Web Design, Speed Optimization, SEO.

## **Work Experience**

#### Front-end Engineer - Contract

HumDov

Nov 2022 - Present (1 month +)

- Collaborate with the rest of the team (including the Backend Engineer and the UI Designer) to implement the UI designs.
- I pay attention to the details of the product we are building and suggest corrections, changes, and improvements.
- Improve my knwoledge of technologies and stay up-to-date with the web development industry in order to deliver high-quality, production-ready code.

#### Lead Front-end Developer - Contract

Yetti Technologies

Aug 2022 - Nov 2022 (4 months)

- I led the Front-end team to ensure proper implementation of design and moved the company's product from 0 to 70% completion.
- I assisted junior developers in areas they had difficulty.
- I reviewed and merged PRs to production.

#### Web Content Writer

#### Decentralize Africa

Feb 2022 - Nov 2022 (10 months)

- Wrote creative content that promote the brand.
- Improved SEO for higher page and post rankings on search engines.
- Did editing and proofreading of existing and new articles to ensure they are of good quality.
- Written over 25 articles so far.

#### Front-end Developer

#### Unlimited.ng

Nov 2020 - July 2021 (9months)

- Taught 5 students HTML, CSS, and JavaScript at a bootcamp hosted by the company.
- Built a website for the bootcamp to automate the registration process and onboarding.
- Awarded as the most punctual employee.
- Collaborated with the marketing team to source for clients via various means and also discuss with clients to know their project requirements.
- Landed the company one paid client.
- Worked on over 15 unique projects in an 9-month period.

#### Soft Skills

- Collaborative
- Communicative
- Emotional Intelligence
- Friendly Personality
- Fast Learner
- Humble, Happy, and Hungry (for knowledge)
- Passion for learning and development
- Problem-Solving
- Self-starter
- Team Leadership

### **Achievements**

- I have written articles on WordPress and other tools I use in building websites.
- Over 20 merged pull requests in 10+ open-source repositories including Ubuntu and Signoz.
- I read about a problem in responsive website design and I built a tool that solves the problem.
- I organized a webinar where I taught 120 students about crypto and Blockchain. Here is a link to the resources (written guides and videos) I made for the webinar.

## Education

#### Univeristy of Ilorin

Bachelor of Education - BEd, Counselor Education

2018 - 2022

- I held 3 different office posts in 3 years in a students' organization.
- I gave a talk on Blockchain at an FTX-organized event that saw over 50 students in attendance.
- Was awarded a Federal Government Scholarship.